<Namespace Name="MonoTouch.GameController">
  <Docs>
    <summary>The GameController namespace provides support for external game controllers.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <para>The Game Controller namespace was added in iOS 7 and adds support for game controllers.</para>
      <para>Game controllers come in two forms: "form-fitting" controllers that contain an iOS device and "extended wireless" controllers that wirelessly connect to an iOS device or a Mac.</para>
      <para>Game controllers must be optional components: game developers must make their game playable by users who do not have game controllers.</para>
      <para>Form-fitting controllers are automatically discovered by the system. Extended wireless controllers are discovered by the system subsequent to the application developer calling <see cref="M:MonoTouch.GameController.GCController.StartWirelessControllerDiscovery" /> and will cause the <see cref="M:MonoTouch.GameController.GCController+Notifications.ObserveDidConnect"/> notification handler to fire. When wireless controller disconnect, the <see cref="M:MonoTouch.GameController.GCController+Notifications.ObserveDidDisconnect"/> notification fires.</para>
      <para>There are two supported profiles for Game Controllers: <see cref="T:MonoTouch.GameController.GCGamepad" /> and <see cref="T:MonoTouch.GameController.CGExtendedGamepad"/>. A <see cref="T:MonoTouch.GameController.GCController"/> will have a non-null value for either its <see cref="P:MonoTouch.GameController.CGController.Gamepad"/> or its <see cref="P:MonoTouch.GameController.CGController.ExtendedGamepad"/> property, the application developer must read those to determine the type. </para>
      <para><see cref="T:MonoTouch.GameController.CGGamepad" />s have two shoulder buttons, a D-pad (see <see cref="T:MonoTouch.GameController. GCControllerDirectionPad"/>), and 4 face buttons labeled Y-B-A-X.</para>
      <para><see cref="T:MonoTouch.GameController.CGExtendedGamepad" />s have the same elements, plus two trigger buttons and two joysticks (see <see cref="T:MonoTouch.GameController.GCControllerAxisInput"/>). Apple conceptual schematics additionally show an LED array, but there is currently no programmatic access to this element.</para>
      <para>There are three ways to read game controller data:</para>
      <para>
        <list type="table">
          <listheader>
            <term>Technique</term>
            <description>Method(s)</description>
            <description>Use</description>
          </listheader>
          <item>
            <term>Polling</term>
            <description>Properties such as <see cref="P:MonoTouch.GameController.GCControllerButtonInput.Pressed" /> or <see cref="P:MonoTouch.GameController.GCControllerDirectionPad.XAxis"/></description>
            <description>Directly read from the game-loop (see <see cref="M:MonoTouch.SpriteKit.SKScene.Update" />).</description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>Event-driven</term>
            <description>Element's <c>ValueChangedHandler</c> property (such as <see cref="M:MonoTouch.GameController.GControllerButtonInput.ValueChangedHandler" />)</description>
            <description>Game Controller processes updates on the main thread. The framework ensures that simultaneously-occurring events result in a series of single callbacks.</description>
          </item>
          <item>
            <term>Coordinated Snapshot</term>
            <description><see cref="M:MonoTouch.GameController.CGGamepad.SaveSnapshot" />, <see cref="M:MonoTouch.GameController.CGExtendedGamepad.SaveSnapshot"/></description>
            <description>Snapshots the controller state. Appropriate for marshalling, serialization, or delayed processing.</description>
          </item>
        </list>
      </para>
      <para>The major classes in the Game Controller namespace are shown in the following illustration:</para>
      <para>
        <img href="GameController.Classes.png" />
      </para>
    </remarks>
  </Docs>
</Namespace>
